

ALESSANDRO Traiola

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

PERSONAL SUMMARY

I'm an energetic frontend addict with more than four years of experience creating and maintaining functional, attractive, and responsive websites. I would describe myself as a self-starter with a growth mindset. I have grit, passion, and determination. There's nothing that can't be learned, there are no skills that can't be gained. I'm highly adept at finding valuable projects to work on and welcome challenges wholeheartedly.

KEY COMPETENCIES

HTML, CSS JavaScript, jQuery React.js, Next.js Redux, Three.js react-three-fiber react-spring Styled Component Tailwind CSS UI/UX AWS MongoDB E-Commerce Responsive Web Design

CONTACT DETAILS

Address: Berliner Str. 74, 13189 Berlin

Number: +49 179 260 7371

Email: aless and rotraio la@gmail.com

Portfolio: aletraweb.com LinkedIn: @alessandro-traiola



WORK HISTORY

Frontend Developer

SOLID WHITE design & digital media GmbH | May 2021 - present

- Responsible for the development of WebGL applications using three.js, react.js, and react-three-fiber frameworks.
- Crafting high-performance websites and applications using industry-standard technologies, such as react.js and next.js.
- Maintaining and improving the company's custom CMS used for client websites and applications.
- Implementing features including metadata integration and camera settings manipulation in platforms such as Blender and Unity.
- Handling customer service inquiries directly to ensure satisfaction.

Web Designer & Developer

SAHU Media AG & Co. KG. | Aug 2019 - Dec 2020

- Constructed and optimized websites
- Built and optimized e-commerce stores
- Solved design and functional problems through coding
- Created logos and other graphics
- Maintained client social media networks
- Managed customer relationships, inquiries and requests
- Awarded for outstanding website production number

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

Webmasters Europe e.V.

JavaScript Developer Certification | Jun 2018 -Aug 2018

Web Design Certification | Apr 2018 - Jun 2018

alfatraining Bildungszentrum

JavaScript Developer Certification | Jun 2018 - Aug 2018 | 97/100 Mark

Learning outcomes: JavaScript, AJAX, JSON, Prototype, Angular.js, Jquery, XML, Node.js, React.js, Vue.js

Web Design Certification | Apr 2018 - Jun 2018 | Full Mark

Learning outcomes: HTML, CSS, Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign

Academind

React.js Certification | Jan 2021 - March 2021

Learning outcomes: React.js, React Hooks, React Router, Redux, Next.js, Framer Motion

SKILLS

Visual communication
Conflict resolution
Eagerness to learn
Working well under pressure
Self-supervising

LANGUAGES

Italian (native) German (fluent) English (fluent) Spanish (beginner)